# **Nathaniel A Herbert**

(512)-704-2018 • Houston, TX 77096 • nateherbert@gmail.com • Personal Webpage

#### **Career Profile**

I'm an M.S. level physicist with 3 years experience in software development and 2 years experience
specializing in detector and simulation software and high energy collision theory. I have worked in
numerous development projects both in and outside of academia across multiple disciplines and have
developed programming experience across numerous platforms. Areas of expertise include:

☐ Python (5+ years)	☐ HTML/CSS (1 year)	Mathematica (5+
☐ SQL (3 years)	☐ Linux/Bash (2 years)	years)
☐ C/C++ (1 year)	☐ Git (1 year)	MATLAB (2 years)
Fortran (1 year)	☐ LaTeX (3 years)	

# **Experience**

# 2017 - 2019 | Cryogenic Dark Matter Search (CDMS) Collaboration | Texas A&M University

- Built a generalized module for calculating recoil parameters for WIMP-nuclei collisions
- Integrated this module into several intertwined systems within a larger simulations framework
- Module and network are built in a combination of C and C++, validated using ROOT

# 2016 - 2016 | Faculty Staff Research Scientist | University of Texas at Austin

- Developed and maintained software in C# for the Neutrino Ettore Majorana Observatory (SuperNEMO) Experiment
- Studied, developed numerical calculations, and programmed mathematical models for eddy current modeling on the L.A.R.E.S. satellite in Fortran

# 2014 - 2016 | Data Services Implementations Engineer | Q2ebanking

- Built and maintained scripts focused on importing and exporting large data sets via batch commands and FTP clients
- Automated nightly processes to parse, manipulate, and import data into separate databases
- Handled communication with internal and external departments to enable smooth transitions

#### 2013 - 2014 | Electrical Engineering Power Systems Assistant | University of Texas at Austin

- Exposed to a wide variety of projects in power systems, specifically focused on the integration of wind energy into the electrical grid
- These projects included research on fault locating techniques, power system simulation programs, time-of-use schedules for electrical vehicles, and several more

#### 2011 - 2012 | Laser Relativity Satellite Temperature Modeling | University of Texas at Austin

- Wrote programs in Mathematica modeling the heat distribution of the L.A.R.E.S. satellite under the guidance of Dr. Phuc Nguyen
- This work assisted in a cooperative effort attempting to test the theory of general relativity

### **Education**

# 2017 - 2019 | Texas A&M University at College Station | M.S. in Experimental High Energy Particle Physics

Collaboration: Cryogenic Dark Matter Search (SuperCDMS)

GPA: 3.72

#### 2011 - 2014 | University of Texas at Austin | Physics B.S.

Society of Physics: Honors Society 2012-2014
Bachelors of Science Physics Scholarship 2011, 2012, 2013

GPA: 3.44

## 2010 - 2011 | University of Texas at San Antonio | Physics B.S.

Alpha Lambda Delta Honors Society 2010-2011

GPA: 3.91

